# ISAAC DENNIS NYARKOH

P. O. Box LG 221, Legon - Accra Cell: +233 24 2847434 | +233 509572677 tawiah82@gmail.com

### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Successful Computer Science Professional with 8+ years teaching and research experience in ICT Education and National Development, Data Mining and Big Data Analytics. A team player, solution oriented, good communication skills, well organized with good sense of humour. Have sound knowledge of Information Technology and Computer Science practice.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **MSc. Information Technology**

Sikkim Manipal University - India, December 2014

Thesis: Enhancing the execution of application through parallel computing

# **B.Ed. Information Technology**

University of Education, Winneba – Ghana, July 2011

Action Research: Using Interactive Multimedia Software Tools to Arouse and Sustain Students' Interest in the Study of ICT - A Case Study of Komfo Anokye Senior High School - Kumasi

## Teachers Certificate A, June 2004

Foso College of Education, Assin Foso – Ghana

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

**Tutor**, Accra College of Education – February 2016 – present

Fully responsible for all aspects of course development, instruction and assessment.

- Introduction to ICT, 1 Semester, 324 teacher trainees
- Computer Networks and Internet Basics 1 Semester, 324 teacher trainees
- Multimedia Technology and its Integration into Education 1 Semester, 324 teacher trainees
- MS Office Applications 1 Semester, 324 teacher trainees
- Supervise teacher trainee students' research work in areas of Mathematics, ICT, Science, English and Education.

Assistant Lecturer, UEW-IDeL (ATRACO STUDY CENTRE, ACCRA) – 2017 – present

I handle the following courses

- Introduction to Information and Communication Technology
- Microsoft Office Application
- Instructional Technology

**Lecturer**, BlueCrest College – Accra Campus – March 2018 – 2020

Fully responsible for all aspects of course development, instruction and assessment.

- Human Computer Interface, Semester VII, 38 students
- Protocol and Inter-Networking Standards, Semester III, 58 students
- Configuring and Implementing Enterprise Networks
- Deploying and Configuring Business Desktops, Semester II, 15 students
- Platform Technologies, Semester II, 15 students
- Deploying and Troubleshooting Open Source OS, Semester II, 15 students

**Tutor**, Jackson Educational Complex, Accra Campus – January 2018 – 2020

Hold tutorials in ICT for Level 100 education students as well as mark, record and submit scores of assignments and end of semester exams.

**Assistant Lecturer,** University of Education, Winneba – Accra College of Education Study Centre – Distance - October 2018

Responsible teaching of Introduction to Information and Communication Technology and Educational Technology

**Mobile Registration Workstation (MRW) Technician/Trainer**, National Identification Authority, - November 2017 – February 2018.

Responsible for training officers who will serve as Data Entry Clerks during the mass registration exercise.

**Tutor**, Assin Nsuta Senior High School, September 2011 – July, 2016 Fully responsible for all aspects of course development, instruction and assessment for SHS 1-3

**Teacher**, Ekumfi Egyankwaa/Owuya D/A JHS, Ekumfi District Assembly, September 2004 – July 2007.

Fully responsible for all aspects of subject teaching and assessment.

- Integrated Science
- Mathematics
- Ghanaian Language

## PROFESSIONAL & COLLEGE SERVICE

Database, Systems and Networks Administrator, Accra College of Education, Accra, 2016 – Present.

Conduct professional development workshops on new technology tools for colleagues and supervisors, Accra College of Education, Accra, 2016 – Present.

Website Management, Accra College of Education, Accra, 2016 – Present.

LAN Installations, Accra College of Education, 2016

# **CONFERENCES, SEMINARS AND WORKSHOPS**

Springboard Roadshow 2012 (**Theme**: Promoting Excellence Through Innovation and Technology

Predictive Analytics Specialist with SPSS Modeler V16, IBM, October 2015

Workshop on Academic Writing, GIMPA School of Technology, 2014

Commonwealth Learning Online Distance Education Conference (Commonwealth, Ghana), 2013

## PROFESSIONAL ASSOCIATIONS

Colleges of Education Teachers Association Ghana (CETAG), Member.

Ghana National Association of Teachers (GNAT) - Ghana, Member.

Institute of ICT Professionals of Ghana (IIPGH) - Member

# **REFERENCES**

Dr. Samuel A. Atintono, Principal, Accra College of Education. Mobile: +233 206212000

Mr. Maxwell Dogbefu, Department of Information Technology, University of Education, Winneba – Kumasi Campus. Mobile: +233 243337486

Mr Benjamin Tettey, HOD Mathematics/ICT, Accra College of Education. Mobile +233 244706765